City Street Blocks Vol. 1 documentation
Promo screenshots taken with
quality settings - Ultra (Edit / Project settings / Quality)
Anisotropic Textures - Forced on
For First Person Character camera effects see 
City Street Blocks Vol. 1 Player / camera Settings document


Prefab scene (MW_CSB_V.1 Prefab) contains:

Facades: MW STREET FACADE 01
17 houses types on 9 2K textures are split to: attic, top part/s,
bottom part (shop/entrance), sun blinds etc. They are modular so you can combine them by stacking together and on top of each other as you like creating desired house or city block.
MW STREET FACADE 01 FRAG - individual parts display.

Side walls: MW SIDE WALLS 01
Four of them are four story and spit by level so you can use them for finishing sides or backs of  houses. One of them is street wall split in 2 pieces.
MW SIDE WALLS 01 FRAG - individual parts display.

Roofs:  MW ROOFS 01
48 modular roof pieces including flat, double sloping, hip and special with 5 types of materials. They are sorted in rows of pieces that fit together and by material. Some double sloping and hip types are made for certain facades bud all the sets have modular closing parts so they can be placed on top.

Scale:
Keep in mind, when creating houses or blocks sometimes you will have to scale individual prefabs or groups  - do not apply changes of scale on finished part otherwise it will affect scale on the source prefab and can damage previous composition. In case you create a prefab from your composition (like a house) then it is ok to apply possible changes thus this will not affect individual prefabs scale in lower hierarchy.


Terrain:  MW TERRAIN 01
39 connectable square pieces stacked in groups that connect to each other in most logical manner. Align pieces by the corner (with V key) and rotate by 90 (or 180 or 270) degrees if needed as they rotate around the center.
MW TERRAIN DEMO 01 from city streets checkerboard included.

Demo scene: (MW_CSB_V.1 Demo) is more important for urban environment project creation. There you will find 43 original block composed of included assets as described above  and 178 overall block variations with prefabs.
Front parts of BLOCK 01 and BLOCK 02 represent actual real street this package was created from and all the rest are assembled by combining these components.

MW_CSB_V.1 Demo contains:

Prefab folders from MW_CSB_V.1 Prefab:
MW STREET FACADE 01
MW SIDE WALLS 01
MW ROOFS 01
MW TERRAIN 01
For assembling your own city blocks an terrain platform
MW TERRAIN DEMO 01 
from city streets checkerboard - first example of terrain platform
+
MW City Street Blocks V1 DEMO - preassembled city district:
- MW TERRAIN DEMO 02 - second example of terrain platform

- MW BLOCKS 01-10, 11-20, 21-30, 31-43 these folders (scene objects)
contain preassembled block that can be changed to your liking and made into prefabs afterwards.
Block Names : BLOCK 14 III  means Block variant 14, III third copy in the scene. Each could be slightly different.

- MW BLOCKS 01-10, 11-20, 21-30, 31-43 NP (Nested Prefabs) contain prefabs from compositions in folders above these are essential for fast environment assembly.
Prefabs location: _MW STREET BLOCKS 01 in project hierarchy.
Block Names : BLOCK 16 III  means Block variant 16, III means another modification. So each prefab with a different name is original (though they might sometimes differ just slightly) - BLOCT 16 is first variant (distributed in the scene several times) will keep same name and BLOCK 16 III is next variant of it - it does not mean BLOCK 16 II is missing it is just a prefab of a different composition. Most of the times differences are significant so in the end there are more variants of the block than just those 43 originally named. 
If you decide to assemble your own block use:
_STREET_FACADE_01, _SIDE_WALLS_01, _ROOFS_01
When doing so perhaps a good idea is to group them in scene object (folder) similar to those in demo scene, they are named as BLOCK 01 etc. - ideally create new prefab in the end. BLOCK prefabs in Demo scene frequently uses components that are slightly scaled - Scale paragraph.

We decided not to stack more than 3 same facade pieces on top of each other in demo while the character of the houses does not correspond with tall / high rise buildings.


Day / Night Scene lighting setup:

Day lighting is default scene setup :

- Materials set up with emission switched OFF

-  _MW Skybox / MAT/ Skybox 21_pan 
(Skybox 17 and Skybox 20 are also available for day lighting) in project hierarchy. You can adjust to your liking by tempering with Tin color, Exposure and Rotation. Currently setup for matching SUN position and north south orientation.

- SUN / Directional Light SUN DAY - switched ON (in scene hierarchy)
You can adjust to your liking by tempering with Tin Color, Intensity etc.




Night lighting setup

- Materials set up:	
_MW SIDE WALLS 01 / MAT - in project select first 4 and switch emission ON
_MW STREET FACADE 01 / MAT - in project select all and switch emission ON

-  _MW Skybox / MAT/ apply M02_pan (adjust if you like)

- SUN / Directional Light SUN DAY - switch OFF (in scene)
Directional Light SUN NIGHT or Directional Light SUN DUSK - 
switch ON (adjust if you like)

-LIGHTS - switch ON (lights for night scene)


LOD - Level of detail on prefabs:
Terrain setup: LOD 1 - 40%, LOD 2 - 15%, Culled 4%
Facades, Side walls, Roofs setup as default:
LOD 1 - 25%, LOD 2 - 13%, Culled 1%
If you choose to adjust these values for performance or any other reasons 
do so in Project directory (_MW ROOFS 01, _MW STREET FACADE 01 etc.)
Unfortunately you have to set one at a time.
Do not adjust them in scene - you would have to apply the changes and doing so you also change current scale to all the piece of the kind and as mentioned in Scale section this can damage previous composition of your houses or existing blocks .


